The World's Best-Loved Musical! The Memory Will Live Forever!
Cats is a music, fantasy film directed by David Mallet.
"Jellicle" cats join for a Jellicle ball where they
rejoice with their leader, Old Deuteronomy.
One cat will be chosen to go to the "Heavyside Layer" and be reborn.
Grizabella, played by Elaine Paige.
Gus the Theatre Cat, played by John Mills.
Old Deuteronomy, played by Ken Page.
Bombalurina, played by Rosemarie Ford.
Munkustrap, played by Michael Gruber.
Rum Tum Tugger, played by John Partridge.
Cats is a 1998 British direct-to-video musical film based on the 1981 stage musical by Andrew
Lloyd Webber, itself based on Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats (1939) by T.
Lloyd Webber oversaw orchestration and called on Gillian Lynne, the
show's original choreographer, to train the cast members.
David Mallet served as the director of this production.
The film is a recreation of the stage musical, but with new staging and
significant edits made to reduce the runtime for television broadcast.
It was filmed at the Adelphi Theatre in London in 1997, with the cast selected from
various past and (then) present international productions of Cats.
Initially released to VHS and subsequently DVD and Blu-ray, the film has since
been shown on television channels including PBS, BBC and Ovation TV.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, stage show, based
on play or musical, live performance, slow motion.